<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<game>
  <name>Mū Tōrere</name>
  <code>mutorere</code>
  <history>Mū Tōrere is a game that gives the strong misconception as an “easy” game to play. Early settlers were often beaten when playing against Māori players due to carelessness. A game that requires a surprising amount of wits and skill, Mū Tōrere is a two-player game that originated from Māori tribes. Since Mū Tōrere existed much longer than recorded, the complete history of this game is incomplete. The game was first recorded by Europeans or Polynesian seafarers in the 1850s. These early settlers discovered a local game that was played by the Ngati-Porou tribe of the Māoris of the East Cape district of New Zealand. However, during the discovery, Mū Tōrere was just starting to lose interest among the tribe thus was never described to the general public. It was till the game was described in R.C.Bell's Board and Table Games, volume 2 (Oxford University Press 1969) that the game became popular again.</history>
  <board>Mū Tōrere is played on an eight-pointed star. The center of the star is referred to as the “pūtahi” and the endpoints of the star are referred to as the “kewai”.[img src="a.svg" alt="a" width="300" height="300"]</board>
  <pieces>The first player moves around four pieces of one color, and the second player moves around four pieces of another color. The pieces are initially arranged on the board as follows:[img src="mutorere.svg" alt="a" width="300" height="300"]</pieces>
  <tomove>At all times there will be one unoccupied point of the star. Move one of your pieces that is adjacent to the unoccupied point to the unoccupied point. Two pieces may not occupy the same point and a piece may not jump over another piece.</tomove>
  <towin>Leave your opponent with no legal moves. You win if your opponent has no pieces adjacent to the unoccupied point, i.e., your opponent's pieces are all trapped.</towin>
  <rules>Example piece movements are shown in the following animation:[img src="c.svg" alt="a" width="300" height="300"]</rules>
  <strategies/>
  <variants/>
  <alternates/>
  <pictures/>
  <references>
    <reference>The board game of Mu Torere, New Zealand in History, 2005</reference>
    <reference>Jelliss, George. "Mu Torere" The Games and Puzzles Journal 17(2006).</reference>
    <reference>Mu-Torere - Maori game from New Zealand, Sandy Greenfarb, 2006</reference>
  </references>
  <links/>
  <gamescrafters>
    <gamescrafter>Joe Jing (Backend, Solving)</gamescrafter>
    <gamescrafter>Jeff Chous (Backend, Solving)</gamescrafter>
    <gamescrafter>Jingfan "Harry" Xia (GamesmanUni GUI)</gamescrafter>
    <gamescrafter>Cameron Cheung (GamesmanUni GUI)</gamescrafter>
  </gamescrafters>
</game>
