<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<game>
  <name>Quick Chess</name>
  <code>quickchess</code>
  <history>Quick Chess was invented by Joe Miccio in 1991 and is a chess variant.</history>
  <board>The standard Quick Chess board is a 6x5 board of squares.&#13;
Starting position: One horse, king, queen, rook, bishop, and knight in the back row, and five pawns in front of them; all of one color. The other color "mirrors" this on the opposite side of the board.</board>
  <pieces>The pieces consist of the pieces used in chess - king, queen, rook, bishop, knight, and pawn.</pieces>
  <tomove>Each player takes turns making one valid move.</tomove>
  <towin>Checkmate the opponent's king.</towin>
  <rules>Players alternate making legal moves. White moves first.&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
King - May move to any adjacent square.&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
Queen - May move in any direction any number of squares.&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
Rook - May move up, down, left, or right (but not diagonally) any number of squares.&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
Bishop - May move diagonally any number of squares.&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
Knight - May move to a space that is two squares and one square to the left/right away, making a L shape. The knight may jump over pieces when moving.&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
Pawn - May move forward one square or may capture a piece by moving diagonally one square (no two square initial moving like in standard chess). [Note: Pawns may only be promoted to a captured piece]</rules>
  <strategies/>
  <variants>
    <variant>
      <name>Misere</name>
      <description>Get your king checkmated.</description>
    </variant>
  </variants>
  <alternates/>
  <pictures>
    <picture>[img src="quickchess_01.jpg" alt="quick chess" width="200"]</picture>
  </pictures>
  <references>
    <reference>Chess Variants. Quick Chess. 18 Feb 2007. &lt;http://www.chessvariants.org/small.dir/quick.html&gt;.</reference>
  </references>
  <links/>
  <gamescrafters>
    <gamescrafter>Adam Abed</gamescrafter>
    <gamescrafter>Aaron Levitan</gamescrafter>
  </gamescrafters>
</game>
