<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<game>
  <name>Rubik's Checkers</name>
  <code>rubikscheckers</code>
  <history>Rubik's Checkers is a game that is similar to checkers. The popular Rubik's games were originally invented by Ernö Rubik.</history>
  <board>The standard Rubik's Checkers board is a variable grid of squares.&#13;
Starting position: A specific number of kings for each player on opposite sides of the board.</board>
  <pieces>There are two pieces - kings and men. Kings become men when jumped over by a king.</pieces>
  <tomove>Each player takes turns making one valid move.&#13;
Valid Moves:&#13;
Kings may move diagonally, forward, or backward. A king may jump over an opponent's piece if the space it jumps to is empty. Multiple jumps are possible (like in regular checkers). When a king jumps over an opponent's king, that king is demoted to a man. If the king jumps over an opponent's man, then that man is removed from the board. When a player's king jumps over the same player's man, that man is promoted back to a king.&#13;
A man may only move backwards, not forward. A man cannot jump or capture any piece.&#13;
On your turn, a piece in your home row may be promoted to a King.</tomove>
  <towin>Eliminate all of the opponents pieces or prevent them from moving.</towin>
  <rules>Players alternate making legal moves.</rules>
  <strategies/>
  <variants>
    <variant>
      <name>Misere</name>
      <description>Eliminate all of your own pieces or prevent all of your pieces from moving.</description>
    </variant>
  </variants>
  <alternates/>
  <pictures>
    <picture>[img src="rubikscheckers_01.jpg" alt="rubik's checkers"]</picture>
  </pictures>
  <references>
    <reference>Toys in the Attic.  Rubik's Checkers Challenge.  18 Feb 2007. &lt;http://www.toysintheattic.biz/products/winningmoves/rubiks.htm&gt;.</reference>
    <reference>ESP Plus. Rubik's Checkers Challenge. 18 Feb 2007. &lt;http://www.espplusnc.com/store/merchant.mv?Screen=PROD&amp;Store_Code=ESP&amp;Product_Code=WM5012&gt;.</reference>
  </references>
  <links/>
  <gamescrafters>
    <gamescrafter>Johnny Tran</gamescrafter>
    <gamescrafter>Steve Wu</gamescrafter>
  </gamescrafters>
</game>
