<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<game>
  <name>Topitop</name>
  <code>topitop</code>
  <history>Topitop is a wooden game created by Thierry Denoual and is made by BlueOrange Games.</history>
  <board>The standard Topitop board is a 3x3 grid of squares.&#13;
Starting position: Nothing on the board. Each player chooses a color and gets 2 buckets of that color.</board>
  <pieces>There are four different basic pieces in Topitop - red buckets, blue buckets, small sand piles, and large sand piles. The sand piles belong to any player. A sand castle or "castle piece" can be made by placing a small sand pile on a large sand pile. A "bucket piece" can be made by placing a bucket on a small sand pile. Lastly, a red/blue sand castle can be made when a bucket is on a castle piece. Only buckets and pieces with a specific color bucket on it are in control of the respective player.</pieces>
  <tomove>Each player takes turns making one valid move and CANNOT reverse the opponent's move that was just made.&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
1) Place one of your buckets or one of the small or large sand piles on any free space on the board&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
2) Move one of your buckets or any small or large sand pile already placed on the board from one square to another (one space at any time in any direction)&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
   a) Any piece already on the board can be moved to an adjacent free space.&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
   b) A bucket can go on top of a small sand pile.&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
   c) A small sand pile can go on top of a large sand pile.&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
   d) A small sand pile with a bucket on its top can go on top of a large sand pile.&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
   e) A bucket can go on top of a sand castle. &lt;br/&gt;  NOTE: You CANNOT place a piece on top of another piece (from off the board to on top of a piece already on the board). Pieces must be MOVED on top of other pieces&lt;br/&gt;&#13;
3) Move any combination of sand piles with your buckets on top, or any sand castle, to any free space.</tomove>
  <towin>Be the first player to have two buckets on top of two sand castles (small sand pile on large sand pile).</towin>
  <rules>Whoever is blue goes first. The players alternate making legal moves. Whenever a player cannot make a legal move, he or she passes the turn to the other player.</rules>
  <strategies/>
  <variants>
    <variant>
      <name>Misere</name>
      <description>Force the opponent to form two red/blue sand castles.</description>
    </variant>
  </variants>
  <alternates/>
  <pictures>
    <picture>[img src="topitop_01.jpg" alt="topitop"]</picture>
    <picture>[img src="topitop_02.gif" alt="topitop"]</picture>
    <picture>[img src="topitop_03.jpg" alt="topitop"]</picture>
  </pictures>
  <references>
    <reference>BlueOrange Games.  Topitop.  5 Feb 2007. &lt;http://www.blueorangegames.com/topitop.php&gt;.</reference>
  </references>
  <links/>
  <gamescrafters>
    <gamescrafter>Mike Hamada</gamescrafter>
    <gamescrafter>Alex Choy</gamescrafter>
  </gamescrafters>
</game>
